<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-06-10T12:58:12-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Paul A Nakroshis</title><subtitle>This is my github homepage. I am an Associate Prof. of Physics at the University of Southern Maine in Portland, ME. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Integrating Computation throughout our physics curriculum</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/physics,/computation,/python,/julia/2021/06/10/Computation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Integrating Computation throughout our physics curriculum" /><published>2021-06-10T12:35:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-06-10T12:35:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/physics,/computation,/python,/julia/2021/06/10/Computation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/physics,/computation,/python,/julia/2021/06/10/Computation.html">&lt;p&gt;This summer and fall, I will be writing computational physics problem set questions in the form of Jupyter Notebooks. 
This is in support of a Maine Space Grant I received to help integrate computing throughout our University of Southern Maine 
physics curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more than a hundred years, physics students have primarily learned physics by being handed weekly analytical paper and pen questions.&lt;br /&gt;
But this is an extreme limitation to the types of problems which can be solved, and with computing now readily available, it makes sense to integrate computational problems into this mix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing so allows one to
	- solve problems that do not admit analytic solutions
	- easily integrate visual simulations 
	- build physical intuition by real time interaction with solutions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My work will involve creating problems for &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; our upper level physics courses. I will organize these 
questions by course (as most physics departments have similar course requirement for B.S. in Physics), and
will make the questions freely available as Jupyter notebooks in both Julia (my new favorite language) and Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look for more info here as I create content. I will also make solutions available to faculty from other institutions,
and will (once I figure out how to manage this) welcome question additions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="physics," /><category term="computation," /><category term="python," /><category term="julia" /><summary type="html">This summer and fall, I will be writing computational physics problem set questions in the form of Jupyter Notebooks. This is in support of a Maine Space Grant I received to help integrate computing throughout our University of Southern Maine physics curriculum.</summary></entry></feed>